# **Kevin Gorham**

Email: Kevin.Gorham@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/2WRha5a | Github: github.com/KGorham05 | Portfolio: FindKevinG.com

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

**Full-Stack Web Developer** specializing in the MERN stack. Lifelong dedication to learning, highly skilled interpersonal communicator, and servant leader with the technical skills to deliver projects on time and under budget. Known amongst peers as calm under pressure, communicative, easy to work with and happy to help.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

UI Web Technologies: React.js, Express, Node, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSX, AJAX, jQuery, Bootstrap, OAuth,

Google Authentication, PHP, Wordpress, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Selenium

**Databases:** MySql + Sequelize, MongoDB + Mongoose, Firebase

Version Controls: Git, Github, Gitlab, Bash

# **APPLICATIONS**

# Aftermath Lab | https://www.aftermathlab.com

- **Summary**: E-commerce site using wordpress CMS.
- Focus: Full design, development, domain registration and hosting. Built custom wordpress theme.
- Tech: CSS, JavaScript, Google Domains, Sitegrounds hosting, gSuite, Wordpress, PHP, Stripe, BitPay

The Elite 4 | https://github.com/KGorham05/mist | https://pokemon-fan-game.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary**: Pokemon fan site with a game created, news scraping, and chat.
- Focus: Lead team, created real time game chat using Socket.io, React
- **Tech**: MongoDB, Express, Node, React

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **DJO Global** QA Engineer

November 2019-Current

Tested all code released in a scrum/agile environment. Wrote detailed test notes using testrails, created automated tests using Selenium in Ruby. Provided UI/UX feedback, and trained the customer success team on new features.

# **UCSD Coding Bootcamp - Trilogy Education** *Teaching Assistant & Tutor*

August

2019-Current

Worked closely with instructor to teach the MERN stack to ~20 students in a classroom setting. Covered everything from HTML, CSS, and JS to database technologies such as MySql, MongoDB, and Firebase. jQuery, Bootstrap, Express, Node, PWAs, React also covered. Full curriculum can be found at <a href="https://bit.ly/2TiEFmG">https://bit.ly/2TiEFmG</a>.

### **Solutions Farms** *Director*

June 2011-June 2018

Applied for and awarded a 1 million dollar grant from the Alliance Healthcare Foundation. Project Managed farm expansion leveraging 10 outside contractors while leading a team of 10 employees. Developed partnership with UCSD engineering department to perform research at our farm. Acquired customers including local school districts, presented at national conferences, gave personal tours to County Supervisors, Senators, and local school field trips.

• Awarded certificate of recognition by VUSD Superintendent Dr. Devin Vodickat for excellence.

# **EDUCATION**

**Full-Stack Web Development Certificate** from University of California, San Diego – May, 2019 **Associates of Arts Degree** in Liberal Arts from Mira Costa College in Oceanside, California – 2014